{
    "id": "b37a8d83e8ac424793cdf5940921d02b",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I don’t like meat but my wife ………………..",
            "description": "We use the auxiliary in structures like these.",
            "answers": [
                "does",
                "likes",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you studied hard, you ………………………… an A grade.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will get",
                "would get",
                "would have got"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What a charming girl …………………………!",
            "description": "In exclamations, the auxiliary goes after the subject.",
            "answers": [
                "is she",
                "she is",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is ……………………. dark that I cannot see anything.",
            "description": "Too and very cannot be followed by a that-clause.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "very",
                "too"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The baby is ……………………… young to walk.",
            "description": "Note the pattern too…to.",
            "answers": [
                "very",
                "too",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You are ………………………. to know better.",
            "description": "When enough modifies an adjective, it goes after that adjective.",
            "answers": [
                "old enough",
                "enough old",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. brilliant idea!",
            "description": "We use what a before a singular countable noun.",
            "answers": [
                "What",
                "What a",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. clever you are!",
            "description": "In exclamations we use how before an adjective without a noun.",
            "answers": [
                "How",
                "What",
                "What a"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………….. the dog, it may bite you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "tease",
                "teases",
                "teased",
                "had teased"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had gone to university, you ………………………….. a better job more easily.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would / could + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "can get",
                "could get",
                "could have got"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If we …………………………. now, we could be there in time.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "started",
                "had started"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My brother does not like sweets. ……………………. do I.",
            "description": "Negative additions to negative remarks are made with nor/neither + auxiliary + subject",
            "answers": [
                "Nor",
                "Neither",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}